# GuilhermeDeMaio

Software Developer



#### contact

R. Ministro Gastão Mesquita, 257 05012-010 São Paulo Brasil

+55 11 9 8393 2639
 guilherme\_nirev
guilherme@nirev.org
 http://nirev.org

**y**/nirev **y**/nirev

in/nirev

### languages

native portuguese fluent english basic french

#### programming

Elixir, Java, Ruby, Javascript, C, Python, HTML, css, bash

#### interests

distributed systems, making a better world, data structures, music, martial arts, science fiction books

## about me

I've been developing software for 10 years, from web apps to embedded media applications. During this time I've come to believe that: - Empathy first, always - Trust is key - Less is more

On the tech side of things, I'm more of a backend/operations type, but I do dabble a bit on the frontend. I enjoy taking part and ownership of where and how applications are deployed and monitored.

I take pride in being part of team. I enjoy giving talks and getting to know people at conferences. I've been a team lead before, and I dislike the term "soft skills". Once you're in a position as such, those so called "soft" skills are exactly what is most important.

## recent experience

September 2015 - \*

Senior Software Engineer at XERPA

São Paulo - Brazil

I joined the company as their first employee to help build the SaaS platform tackling HR bureaucracy in Brazil. We started from day-0 with Elixir and Phoenix on the backend, with the frontend initially in simple html/css/jquery. We eventually migrated the frontend to Clojure-Script using a GraphQL API.

Among things I took part are:

- Bootstrapped the platform using Elixir, Phoenix and PostgreSQL
- Managing infrastructure with Terraform and Ansible
- Built libraries for:
- Authentication and Authorization
- Indexing things to ElasticSearch, as well as defining mappings
- Resizing and manipulating images
- Integrating with payment gateways
- Defining and prioritizing features together with product and business/sales teams. I also did visit "beta" clients in the beginning to get a better understanding of the problems we needed to solve.
- Collaborating heavily with Customer Success team to help streamline client usage after signup, focusing on quickly solving bugs and creating stories to improve the user experience
- Using OCR to identify unique numbers in PDFs, built a document distribution feature which greatly improved sales and customer satisfaction.

November 2012 – September 2015

#### Team Lead (Search and Analytics) at Elo7

São Paulo - Brazil

A marketplace with high traffic and transaction volume. The stack was based on Java, Ruby and Scala on AWS infrastructure. A fast paced environment, with agile practices, and focusing on delivering fast with quality. We measured and logged using StatsD, Graphite, and NewRelic, and deployed constantly. I was leading the Search and Analytics Team: a small team using Solr, Kafka and Spark to improve search and real time reports, and responsible for its infrastructure and pipeline tools.

#### past experiences details available upon request

04/2012to10/2012 - Intern at INRIA Paris-RoquencourtParis - France03/2011to09/2012 - Undergrad Researcher at USP - CHOReOS projectSão Paulo - Brazil08/2010to02/2011 - Software Developer (C/C++) at RR SistemaVitória/ES - Brazil01/2009to12/2010 - Undergrad Intern at Multimedia and Network Research LabVitória/ES - Brazil08/2008to12/2008 - Undergrad Intern at LASSYUniversity of Luxembourg - LU03/2007to12/2007 - Undergrad Intern at NINFA laboratoryVitória/ES - Brazil09/2006to03/2007 - PHP Developer at Lettera SoluçõesVitória/ES - Brazil

## education

2011–2014 Master in Computer Science University of São Paulo - Brazil 2005–2010 B.Sc. in Computer Science Federal University of Espírito Santo - Brazil